Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
["Psycho KiIller"
by Talking Heads playing]
♪ I can't seem to face up to the facts ♪
♪ I'm tense and nervous
And I can't relax ♪
♪ I can't sleep. 'cause my bed's on fire ♪
♪ Don't touch me. I'm a real live wire ♪
♪ Psycho killer. qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
♪ Fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa
Fa better ♪
♪ Run. run. run. run. run. run. run away ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Psycho killer. qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
♪ Fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa. fa
Fa better ♪
♪ Run. run. run. run. run. run. run away ♪
♪ Oh-ho-ho-ho. aye-yi-yi-yi-yi. ooh ♪
[song fades out]
[thunder rumbling]
[sighs]
[siren wailing in the distance]
[thunder continues]
["Psycho Killer" playing loudly upstairs]
[exhales]
[thudding upstairs]
[sighs]
Shit.
♪ Ce que J'ai fait ce soir-là ♪
[sighs]
♪ Ce qu'elle a dit ce soir-là ♪
[doorbell rings]
Hello?
[in French] Excuse me.
Excuse me!
I'm with a patient.
and I can't hear a thing.
We've already...
[neighbor in French] What a rabat-oij!
[indistinct chatter]
[laughter]
[woman on voicemail in French]
You've reached Paula Cohen-Solal.
- Leave a message. Thanks.
- [beeps]
[in French] Yes. it's Dr. Steiner calling.
You've now missed three sessions. Paula.
After three.
I think my concern is justified.
You must pay for the missed sessions.
[automated voice in English] Raba-ouaje.
Phonetic slang for Rabat-joie.
Cockblocker. old biddy.
break balls. frigid. pain in the ass.
[sighs]
[thumping upstairs]
[sighs] Asshole.
- [in French] You're here?
- [in French] Hello.
But... it's not our day.
I know. but I need to speak to you.
Fine...
Don't stand there. Come.
Thanks.
- [clears throat]
- [door closes]
- [Dr. Steiner] Lie down.
- [keys clatter]
- You don't want to lie down?
- Mm.
Fine.
[man] Um...
You remember eight years ago.
when I came here for the first time?
- At first it was to...
- Quit smoking.
Right.
It was a pretext
to undergo a psychoanalysis.
I underwent psychoanalysis.
but never stopped smoking.
So listen.
Last Monday I saw a hypnotist.
Why not lie down?
You'll free-associate better.
Doctor. listen to me.
I'm listening.
- [clears throat]
- [beeps]
[man] François gave me her name.
- My wife's friend...
- I know.
...who's into alternative medicine.
Ms. Grangé in Aubervilliers.
And he... quit smoking. thanks to her.
At first. she spouted some nonsense:
Uh. "Let yourself go." [scoffs]
"What do you see?"
I said. "My parents naked in a house."
Whatever.
It lasted 20 minutes. It was short.
I paid for the session. 50 euros.
Uh. I was puzzled. I went outside.
All of a sudden.
I threw my cigarettes in the trash.
I kept on walking.
then I turned around.
looked at my cigarettes.
and to my surprise.
I threw away my lighter too.
[thunder rumbling]
It's been four days.
- And I haven't smoked.
- [cell phone ringing]
Wild. Almost a week.
[Dr. Steiner] I'll shut it off.
I thought it was on silent mode.
I'm listening. Yes...
[man] I feel freed from something.
Freed from smoking. of course.
And freed from you.
There.
[thunder rumbling]
I want to stop seeing you.
All right. Fine.
Maybe...
we can agree on a date to stop.
- Or I'll refer you to a colleague.
- I'm done.
My wife did the math.
Eight years. once a week.
excluding vacations.
I've spent 32.000 here.
Plus 8.000 wasted on cigarettes.
We're done.
Goodbye.
- [door closes
- [cell phone buzzing]
[woman on voicemail in French]
Hello. I'm Valérie. Paula's daughter.
I saw you tried calling several times.
I have some very sad news.
She's passed away.
I'd like to invite you to...
join us.
We'll be gathering together tomorrow.
Thank you.
[suspenseful music playing]
A PRIVATE LIFE
[suspenseful music continues]
Thanks for coming.
Mom's room is packed.
I'll ask her students to leave.
You know what happened to her?
- No idea. It was very sudden.
- Ah.
[indistinct chatter]
[cell phone buzzing]
[woman] You'll awaken the dybbuk.
The what?
The dybbuks. evil spirits.
[Dr. Steiner] Dybbuk.
[man 1] Hello.
I taught with her at Jules Ferry.
[man 2] Good of you to come.
We'll all gather before her.
Come in...
Aaron. are you coming?
Aaron. come.
[indistinct chatter]
[woman weeping]
[praying in Hebrew]
- [woman screams] He fainted.
- Roll him on his side.
Put his legs on a cushion.
- [man 3] Bring water.
- Don't!
I'm a doctor.
- Where's the bathroom?
- There.
[woman] Can someone come?
Dad. what's wrong?
[father speaks indistinctly]
- Sit up. breathe.
- [father] Oh! [mumbles]
[exhales]
- [Dr. Steiner] Take this. sir.
- How kind. Thank you.
- Thank you. I'll be fine...
- [Dr. Steiner] Breathe.
Who are you?
Lilian Steiner.
I was treating your wife for nine years.
- I'm sorry.
- Get out.
- [shouting] Get out!
Why are you here? Who let you in?
This is my home! How dare you?
Throw her out!
[in English] Her husband's reaction
is unexpected.
Aggression towards me.
Redirected guilt towards the therapist
- and unprocessed emot--
- [recorder clicks]
- ...redirected guilt...
- [clicks]
- Shit.
Shit.
[suspenseful music playing]
[in French] Sit! Are you okay?
[in French] Sit down. sir. I'm fine.
[suspenseful music playing]
[children shouting]
[doorbell rings]
[in French] You rang?
I said not to wake up Joseph.
- Call first.
- I woke him?
No. but you could have.
Scolding me for something hypothetical?
Which didn't happen.
- Know what that's called?
- No. and I don't want to.
Twenty-five euros for five?
Order 50 for me.
No. 100.
Five hundred for minidiscs?
They're prehistoric!
Why not try something modern?
I like being able to hold them.
They can get lost or damaged.
Because I can lose them
makes them precious.
Spare me.
[sniffling]
Five hundred euros. Damn.
It's for my work.
How much was your computer?
- You come only when you need something.
- [sniffling]
[in English] There.
- Are you sick?
[in French] Yes. no. not really.
Do you have any hand sanitizer?
- There.
- Ah.
Buy something that'll make you happy.
I'd be happy if you came when he's awake.
[scoffs] It's not my fault
that babies sleep a lot.
Your order is confirmed.
- Okay. [sniffles]
- [baby cooing]
Ah! Wanna see Joseph?
[sighs] No. I have to go
to an appointment.
More important than 30 seconds with us?
- Come.
- [baby crying]
- What's wrong. kiddo?
- [continues crying]
You hungry?
Shh. Sh-sh-sh-sh. Calm down.
It's early.
You have a rash.
- I'm leaving. honey.
- [cooing]
I'm sick. covered in germs.
I don't want to get close.
Love you.
[percussive music playing]
- [woman] It's been ages!
- [Lilian] Is he in?
- You can go in.
- Thanks.
[percussive music continues]
[Lilian sighs]
Lilian?
You're okay?
- Bad time?
- Not at all.
Is all well?
No.
I...
I don't know what I have.
I caught something.
- Mind examining me?
- Not at all.
Have a seat.
Your last eye exam was...
- With you.
- [water running]
[Lilian sighs]
[machine whirs]
- Your chin there.
- Okay.
- Have you seen Joseph recently?
- Yes.
I just stopped by. He was asleep.
He sleeps a lot.
I find him very much awake for his age...
Two months.
- He could pass for three.
- [Lilian chuckles]
Julien is young.
To be a father. Right?
Young?
- You were his age.
- Exactly.
[machine whirs]
- Push. Push your chin.
- Mm.
[beeping]
[doctor] It keeps on flowing. honey...
[Lilian laughs softly]
You call me "honey"?
[machine beeps then whirs]
- First time I've seen you cry.
- [scoffs]
- I know.
- It suits you.
I'm not crying. It's my eyes.
- Find anything?
- No. it's all normal.
Got eye drops or a placebo for me?
Uh. artificial tears
can hydrate the cornea.
but just wait for it to stop.
[scoffs] I can't wait.
I have patients. work...
Did something happen?
No. nothing special.
- So it was just a pretext to see me.
- [scoffs] No. not at all.
You can text me to go have dinner.
It's easier.
[laughs] I never think about you.
I mean it. Never.
While fighting with Julien earlier.
I thought.
"Poor kid inherited
his father's lousy temper."
[sighs]
[in English] What the fuck?
[in French] Sorry.
[percussive music playing]
- Hello.
I'm Valérie.
- Paula Cohen-Solal's daughter.
- [Lilian] I recognize you.
I need to speak with you.
I can't now.
I have a patient in a few minutes.
- Some other time...
- I can wait at the café.
No problem.
Come.
[suspenseful music playing]
So... how can I help you?
[music ends]
Know how she killed herself?
I had no idea it was a suicide.
She was fine the week before.
and you don't wonder why?
It happens to everyone. Death.
Now that you know. you feel nothing?
I don't feel nothing.
Sorry. I didn't want to make you cry.
Uh. no.
It's not you.
[Lilian sighs]
She swallowed everything you prescribed.
I understand.
You think I'm responsible for her death?
My father thinks so.
I'm talking to you. not him.
She had this in her hand.
Look what she scribbled on the back.
Before she died.
I can't read it.
The writing is distorted.
I think it's a message.
A message...
- For whom?
- Read it!
- Read it out loud.
- [intercom rings]
I can't. I have a patient.
Keep it. Give it back later.
- Come in.
- [beeping]
Valérie...
maybe you know this. maybe not.
but I cannot disclose
anything Paula told me.
It's called
doctor-patient confidentiality.
I need to understand.
How could she do this?
Especially now.
Now that I'm in this state.
What state?
Yes. of course.
How did the funeral go?
We don't know when it is.
Uh. but in the Jewish religion. we...
They need to do an autopsy.
- An investigation.
- There's an investigation?
It's the law with suicides.
It takes time.
[sighs]
[patient in English] We were-- We were
parked by the side of the road. and...
We were parked by the side
of the road.
and I must have been 10 or 11.
We had this. um...
this white minivan with gold trim.
I remember.
It was the same time or a different time.
but the brakes had gone out in the car.
so my mother had to...
to pull the emergency brake.
And...
- [in French] It's hard to say...
- [woman] Before coming.
I realized that...
I just don't get it.
I give my sperm to no avail.
- Why do I feel cut off?
- [woman 2] I claw and claw...
The cats' eyes.
I scratch.
[suspenseful music playing]
[sighs]
I think about your hands.
Your hands on my body.
- [door closes]
- [sighs]
Shit!
["Psycho Killer" playing upstairs]
[patient on recording]
Last Monday. I saw a hypnotist.
François gave me her name...
[fast forwarding]
Grangé. in Aubervilliers.
He quit smoking thanks to her.
At first she spouted some nonsense...
[rhythmic music playing]
[Jessica] It's not ophthalmological?
- [Lilian] No.
- Maybe see someone?
[scoffs] I'm a shrink.
If I were depressed. I'd know it.
I can't just stop you from crying.
Why not?
Because you still need to cry.
We don't bandage uncleaned wounds.
You're in mourning.
Very deep mourning.
I can tell.
You're not here alone.
There's someone else.
[scoffs]
I see no one besides you.
It's a woman.
She is blonde.
Uh...
I just lost a patient.
And it's...
not the first time a patient dies.
She was a patient. not a friend.
Listen. what I can propose.
if you agree.
is a memory-based therapy.
And...
[breathes deeply]
...you're ready to let go.
[laughs]
First time I've heard that.
All right.
[clears throat] Can I make an appointment?
No. we'll deal with it right away.
You waste no time.
First you said keep crying...
- I like it when people heal quickly.
- Ah...
Not like shrinks?
Shall we?
Yes.
[beeps]
You're recording this?
Yes. I'll give it to you afterwards.
It will help the session seep in.
What you hear may surprise you.
A lot of the things you say
will be forgotten.
Do I have your email?
Hm...
It's as you wish. I'm flexible.
Well...
I'm flexible too. Huh?
There.
So. let yourself go.
Let go.
[Lilian exhales deeply]
Look without seeing.
[exhales]
Now close your eyes.
Everything is black.
You can hear your heart beating.
You are...
in your mother's belly.
[sighs]
Lilian. stop confusing skepticism
and intelligence.
Your irony is an expression of your fear.
You are in your mother's belly.
[fan whirring]
[Jessica] You are a fetus.
[ominous music playing]
[Jessica] Step forward.
[Lilian exhales]
Keep moving.
You see a door.
Behind the door.
you see stairs.
When you're ready. go down them.
[chimes tinkling]
[Jessica] Very good.
[heartbeat thumping slowly]
[Lilian in English] It's snowing.
[Jessica] Go on. take your time.
You see a door.
Open it.
- [siren wailing]
- [children shouting]
[Lilian in French] Not this one.
No. please.
[Jessica] Then close it.
[door closes]
At your own pace.
keep going down.
I'm here.
What is the room like?
Can you describe it?
[Lilian] Dark.
Woody.
[indistinct chatter]
The faces are lit up.
Instruments.
[indistinct chatter continues]
[Jessica] Tell me about this room.
[Lilian] There is a woman.
With a cello.
[orchestral instruments tuning]
[Jessica] Go on telling me what you see.
[Lilian gasping]
It's...
It's me.
It's her.
It's Paula. Paula Cohen-Solal. my patient.
We're in an orchestra pit.
[in English] Tuning our instruments.
It's during the war.
There are Germans.
C'est un audience...
[in French] The public is staring at us.
And we love each other.
Madly.
I can sense she is my mistress.
It's wild.
She is very anxious.
- [door closes]
- [in English] Oh! What's happening?
[applause]
[Jessica] What's happening. Lilian?
[Lilian] Simon. her husband.
[inaudible dialogue]
She speaks to me. I can't hear.
I must hear.
Forget about it for now.
[in English] No. no. I need to hear her.
[Jessica] You'll be able
to find the door again.
- [Lilian in French] No.
- Let's go back up the stairs.
When I say so. leave the stage.
- [Lilian] During the concert?
- Leave the stage.
- I must listen to her.
- Leave.
[cries out]
- [Jessica] Leave.
- He's armed.
[Jessica] Go back to the door.
There's another door...
- What do I do?
- [Jessica] Wait there.
[operatic music playing]
Before opening it.
I have something to say.
You won't cry anymore.
It's over.
No more tears.
Now you know
that Paula is part of your life.
She was your mistress.
In another life.
Your pain is normal.
[breathing heavily]
When I say so.
you'll open the door.
- Open the door.
- [gasping]
When ready. open your eyes.
He's armed.
The husband. the conductor. Simon. he's...
You're a receptive subject.
[Lilian gasps]
It's very rare
to go down the stairs so quickly.
[Lilian] Well... [laughs]
I must say. I don't believe any of this.
So...
It's not about believing or not.
You won't cry once you leave my office.
Can I ask you a question?
It's simple.
Have you ever felt
you fell in love with your patient?
Or were unsettled by her?
[scoffs]
All right. Thanks for everything.
What do I owe you?
Fifty. right?
No.
I decide whether I want to be paid.
It's my call.
Will it work anyway?
Yes. it will work anyway.
Don't worry. Here the cure
isn't dependent on money.
You know. Freud stopped hypnosis
because it was much less
interesting financially.
The cure was too quick.
Isn't that borderline anti-Semitic?
We'll stop here. Lilian.
[rabbi] Forty-seven years...
A life unfinished...
Paula leaves behind her
an enormous void.
Here she joins.
a few months later.
her beloved aunt.
Pearl.
Pearl left Paula
her love of books.
- Got a handkerchief?
- Her love of culture.
Her love of the German language.
Thank you. It's very kind.
[rabbi speaking Hebrew]
[continues speaking Hebrew]
- Amen.
- [woman] Amen.
[rabbi in French] God full of compassion.
who resides in heaven...
[continues in French]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music turns rhythmic]
I just don't understand
what I deserve in life.
How do I overcome this?
[sobbing]
Every time I'm scared.
He made me doubt.
[continues sobbing]
I think it's a message.
[Paula on recording] I'm aware of the lie.
- The enormity of the lie.
- [thunder rumbling]
It's too late now.
There's no going back.
The truth would destroy Valérie.
It would really destroy her.
She's too unstable.
You know...
it was my greatest sorrow.
Those children who couldn't hold on.
[Lilian] Fetuses aren't children yet.
Yes.
Simon called them
"our dead children."
[Lilian] And you felt...
he was blaming you?
Part of me ended up embracing
his way of thinking.
He became crazed.
He felt he was the problem.
[Lilian] Meaning?
Valérie...
He knows she's not his.
But you told me Valérie knows.
I lied to you.
I never told her.
It could trigger a crisis.
Terrifying crises.
If she found out. she would kill me.
[rewinding]
I lied to you.
I never told her.
It could trigger a crisis.
Terrifying crises.
If she found out. she would kill me.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Lilian] Aggressivity toward the mother
is normal. but murder?
[woman] You know anything's possible.
I've never encountered it.
Oh. shit! Not true!
I had a colleague in Nice 20 years ago.
I just remembered.
A girl killed her mother
during a psychotic episode
toward the end of her pregnancy.
She stabbed her. I recall.
and disemboweled her.
It was violent.
You see cases of psychic transference
in late pregnancy.
There was another case.
The girl killed everyone.
Her mother and sisters. all poisoned.
Only women.
- Interesting.
- Yes. very.
- Never heard of it?
- No.
Her psychosis predated her pregnancy.
of course.
[cell phone ringing]
Hello?
[sighs]
[cell phone ringing]
UNKNOWN CALLER
Hello. Who is this?
Hello?
["Giorni" by Mina playing over speakers]
Mondays as usual.
I'm a creature of habit.
- May I?
- Of course.
Your eyes?
They're fine. But I need yours.
It concerns my patient.
What are you talking about?
My patient.
The one who...
Yes?
My patient who committed suicide.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
I want to drink a lot in a short time.
I'll join you.
- [cell phone ringing]
- [sighs]
I keep getting phone calls.
Anonymous.
Uh... she'll have the tagliatelle
without cream.
[Lilian] Look.
What do you read?
- [man] It's German?
- She was a German teacher.
- "Kinder" means "children."
- Yes.
- Don't get it dirty!
- Relax...
And "tod..."
Not "tod." "tot." It means "dead."
I...
I get the feeling...
it's a message she left for me.
A message?
Yeah.
I...
Listen. I...
I have an idea. Gaby.
I want you to take it seriously.
- Yes.
- Okay?
- Go on. speak.
- I...
I never detected
the slightest suicidal thought.
It's not normal. in nine years.
I can't have been so wrong.
But...
what are you talking about?
My patient!
I...
I think...
she was murdered.
Murdered?
But by whom and why?
That's the question.
I keep thinking about it.
and instinctively.
I'd say it's her daughter.
She is borderline.
A decompensated personality disorder
doesn't make her a criminal.
- Thank you.
- Eat something.
Not eating?
I am.
Thanks.
Oh. I remember these earrings.
Didn't we drink a lot?
Yeah.
I don't want to go home.
- Merci.
[cell phone ringing]
[sighs] No!
Not again.
You're bothering us. Now stop.
I'm about to sleep with my ex-wife.
Enough already!
Thank you.
- Presumptuous!
- Mm...
You've never seen my place.
I don't want to run into Vera.
Vera's over with.
Two years ago.
I thought you knew.
How would I know?
Did you ever see a hypnotist?
No. Oh. yes. I did.
Once. for snoring.
[chuckles]
What?
- Eh?
- That cracks me up.
You always used to say.
"It's just when I'm in a bad position."
But now...
it doesn't matter.
because you sleep alone. No?
No.
Not every night.
She's married. which is fine.
And you?
Me what?
Did you ever see a hypnotist?
[Lilian] Mm.
- [footsteps]
- [alarm chirps]
[cell phone ringing]
UNKNOWN CALLER
[in English] Shit.
[dog barking]
Valérie--?
[door closes]
[grunts]
- [engine starts]
- [pop music playing over speakers]
[breathing heavily]
[siren wailing]
[in English] Oh. shit.
TWILIGHT TRYST
[scrubbing]
[moans softly]
[chimes tinkling]
[thudding upstairs]
[indistinct voices]
[sighs]
[in English] Shit.
[ominous music playing]
[breathing nervously]
[in French] Who's there?
[thudding]
[footsteps on the stairs]
[dramatic music]
The red liquid on the windshield.
[keyboard clacking]
[officer] So basically.
you're filing a report for stalking.
not for theft.
Call it what you want.
but I'm persuaded it wasn't suicide.
I think it's her daughter.
She's intimidating me.
Searching stuff about her mother's death.
She was looking for the cassettes.
What cassettes?
When I said "died."
it could mean "murder."
Have you been drinking?
No. Well. yes.
But several hours ago.
- How many?
- What?
- Is it against the law now?
- No. uh...
I have hyperosmia.
What?
Long COVID made me sensitive to smells.
So I'm curious when you drank last.
My last glass was at midnight.
Hyperosmia... Never heard of it.
Yes. sorry.
So you were saying...
It could be a murder.
Obviously. it's my place
she searched. Huh?
She who?
Her daughter! Valérie.
Because I know things about her
that I shouldn't know.
What kind of things?
I can't tell you.
Doctor-patient confidentiality.
[sighs] Okay. let's start over...
- Your profession?
- Psychiatrist.
[percussive music playing]
- You okay?
- Yes...
[Gaby] Oh...
I was scared.
[thunder rumbling]
You believe me now?
- What did she want?
- The cassettes.
The cassettes interest her.
Stupid me.
I didn't listen to the last session.
On the 22nd.
Shit...
What happened then?
The motive. obviously!
I must listen to what she said
about Valérie. about him.
- Tell the police?
- Yes.
Why didn't I listen to that last tape?
- [in English] Fuck.
- I'll call a locksmith.
[automated voice] Your call is on hold.
Stay on the line.
[Gaby] Yes. I'm staying on.
Strange profession.
Locksmith?
[laughs] No. psychiatrist.
[hold Muzak playing on phone]
Knowing people's lives. secrets.
without being able to act.
Not being able to do anything.
Nothing at all.
Whereas you...
People come to see you to fix their eyes.
You fix them. What do I fix?
Their souls.
[laughs]
I should have been a gynecologist.
Mm-hm. You'd have excelled.
Is it too late to change lives?
You mean us?
- [laughs]
- Yes. a lock.
I don't know. sir.
- A robbery...
- [sighs]
[thunder rumbling]
[raindrops pattering]
[Paula on recording] Uh... He goes away
two or three days a week.
He has only two
half-days of classes a week.
I encourage him
to spend more time in Chérence.
But I make him pay for it
when he comes back.
It's perverse.
No?
[Lilian] Who is perverse?
We have very different schedules.
He goes to bed early. wakes up late.
I'm the opposite.
It's so banal.
I've developed strategies
not to bother him.
In bed. I think only of him.
of making his sleep better.
But...
he's harsh.
So harsh.
[Lilian] How so?
[sighs]
As if he always has a knife in his voice.
And a gun in his eyes.
It's as if he waits for me
to leave his space to tolerate me.
He wants me gone.
[doorbell rings]
[door unlocking]
Valérie!
Why don't you call me back?
You can't keep showing up unannounced.
I have to see you immediately.
I need help. Lilian.
All right. not in my office.
In the café downstairs.
[in English] Fuck.
Okay.
- Fuck.
- [Gaby on the phone] Allô?
Gaby?
It's her! She's here!
Uh. Valérie.
Her daughter.
I told her to meet me in the café. Come.
[suspenseful music playing]
[sighs] Go on.
[Valérie] I feel so bad.
I'm a monster.
A monster?
- [clattering
- [indistinct chatter]
But... why?
"Monster"-- Why that word?
My mother just inherited from Pearl.
Pearl Friedman. her aunt.
She never told you? It was a big deal.
I loved her too.
She spent her life at the library.
She volunteered at la Mazarine.
She took me there when I was little.
I'd watch her sorting out books all day.
It's a lot of money. a real lot.
It all goes to Paula. but...
now I share it all with Dad.
I had a hard time making ends meet.
I don't know...
My life has changed.
Valérie. everything you feel
seems perfectly normal.
- I'll give you a colleague's number.
- Why not you?
Huh? No. no. No.
You understand?
I can't. We're not allowed.
[Valérie] Yes. you're absolutely right.
I understand my mother better.
She often mentioned you.
But never said your name.
She called you "my twilight tryst."
[laughs softly]
She said she felt good with you.
She said that?
Yes. often.
Dad said she...
fell in love with you.
And Mom answered.
"It's like I've known her...
forever."
[orchestral music playing]
[knocking]
[Lilian] It's not her.
Okay.
No. it must be her father. who's...
not her father-- The husband.
The father isn't the father. Great!
I didn't say a word.
Not a word.
She didn't even take her prescription.
She's not in a manic state.
She gave me the motive.
It's money.
- Money?
- Paula had just inherited.
- It's not her.
- You wanted to knock her out.
- No...
- Fifteen drops at bedtime. Damn!
What? It's a five-milligram pill.
Five mg. in pill form.
- With your handwriting...
- Let me see.
But...
It was tampered with!
- What pharmacy?
- It's written on it.
[Lilian] Wait here.
[indistinct chatter]
Thank you. Goodbye.
- Hello.
- Hello. ma'am.
I'm Dr. Steiner.
the psychiatrist
who treated Paula Cohen-Solal.
She lived in this building.
It's normal to go from pills to drops
for chronic insomnia.
- I've known them for years.
- Nadia. look at me.
I'm not here to alert authorities.
Up to now.
I've only prescribed pills. right?
Absolutely.
And I said the same thing
to Mr. Cohen-Solal.
You mean he picked them up?
He did?
Come on. Nadia.
I just want to know
who picked up the medicine.
Yes. it was her husband.
He always picked up her prescriptions.
I mean. her medicine.
Did he ask for the bottle?
We deciphered the prescription together.
Like me. he read 15 drops.
He said she was unwell.
She was having a rough time.
A family member had died.
[sighs]
Drive!
- Fast. fast!
- Okay.
What is that thing?
I got the caretaker to talk.
And?
He left for the country.
- Where to?
- She didn't say.
I went upstairs to look
and came across this.
Open it.
Are you sure?
At the point we're at...
Now I know why
I never get Amazon packages.
A hair iron.
Long-haired hubby?
Maybe it's for Paula.
It was ordered eight days ago.
Really?
Who orders a hair iron
three days after his wife dies?
We need to find out about the aunt.
The aunt Valérie mentioned.
Why? You think that...
He must have killed her first.
Oh...
[sighs] Paula never mentioned her.
Maybe I forgot or I misheard.
It's impossible.
A lot of loose ends.
Just to end up with a capillary dildo.
Shit. I have to go.
- Wait for me for the rest.
- [laughs]
[Lilian] I often came when there was
that old lady...
She volunteered here.
I forget her name.
Yes. it's Pearl!
Oh. yes. Pearl.
One of our sponsors.
Yes. an old lady. very nice.
Actually. I think she died.
- No.
- A few...
No.
- No what?
- She wasn't very nice.
- But she died.
- Yes.
What of?
- Would you know?
- Not at all.
But she really was not nice.
- All right...
- [man] Lucie?
I'd like to send a condolence letter
to the family.
Would you have her address?
We don't give out that information.
- [man] Lucie. come here!
- Excuse me.
- Can you wait a minute?
- Yes.
[indistinct chatter]
[suspenseful music playing]
Okay. Friedman.
Maiden name: Kinder.
Kinder?
Pearl Kinder.
"Kinder tot."
The death of Pearl.
- No fucking way...
- Madam!
[Jessica on the phone]
No. I don't think so.
You're too rational for that.
Tell me the real reason.
You stopped crying.
so why another session?
She said something to me.
Remember?
I couldn't hear. I have to.
[Jessica] You have a recording
of our session.
I said to use it.
Yes. but there's a missing key.
What if I say no?
[scoffs] Listen. don't be proud.
I apologize.
I was very rude to you.
Not rude. Insulting.
You called me an anti-Semite.
I said "borderline."
But...
I'm sorry.
Forgive me!
[Jessica sighs] No.
- It's impossible.
- I'm coming up!
No. No.
Sorry. Lilian. it's Friday.
I have a train.
How about Monday?
Monday. no. I'm in training.
then I go on vacation.
Goodbye. Lilian.
[line cuts]
On vacation.
[in English] Fucking French.
[percussive music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
- [server] Champagne?
- No. thanks.
[laughter]
[in English] Clearly. you're suffering
from guilt about this patient.
You're building a narrative
from this false memory.
As a doctor. you're supposed
to heal your patients.
Instead. your medication killed her.
What strikes me is the prescription.
The ordonnance.
[scoffs]
[in English] What do you mean?
You know as well as I do that in France.
psychoanalysts aren't allowed
to prescribe.
Well. we knew each other very well.
and she was struggling with insomnia.
You broke standard procedure.
No. I didn't.
I'm fully licensed to prescribe.
I gave them all the information that
they need if they want to press charges.
No. you didn't.
You're in avoidance.
In fact. you don't want
to confront the case itself.
so you go off on a trip
with your hypnotist.
Tell me again how your mother died.
No.
You can't do that.
I'm not your patient anymore.
I'm your colleague.
You haven't changed. Lilian.
You're still so sure of yourself.
I don't know why I came here.
[door shuts]
[sighs]
[keyboard clacking]
[computer chimes]
[Jessica on recording] Behind the doors.
you see stairs.
When you're ready. go down them.
Keep on going.
[Lilian] We're in an orchestra pit.
[Paula] What are you doing?
Where's your head? Your score.
[drum roll]
[applause]
I'm pregnant with your child. my love.
[Lilian] I'm pregnant
with your child. my love.
[laughing softly]
I'm overwhelmed.
But I can't leave like this.
[Jessica] Who asks you to leave?
[Lilian] A stage manager
behind the curtains.
he says to flee.
They're here!
[Jessica] Who?
[Lilian in English] The police.
[in French] The militiamen.
They'll check our IDs.
They'll round us up. We must flee!
[Jessica] Tell me what you see.
[Lilian] Oh! Julien!
He's a militiaman.
[singing opera]
[heart beating]
[Jessica] Julien?
[Lilian in English] It's my son.
[Jessica] What else?
Oh...
He's got a gun.
[gunshot]
- [Lilian gasps]
- [Jessica] What now?
[Lilian gasping]
[opera continues]
[Lilian in English] Hurry up.
[in French] I'm leaving.
I search my pockets.
A postcard.
- [Jessica] Turn it over.
- Chérence.
[Jessica] Leave now. Lilian. Leave!
- Open the door!
- Chérence...
[fingers click]
Chérence.
["Psycho Killer" playing]
[automated voice on GPS]
You go out from Paris.
♪ I can't seem to face up to the facts ♪
♪ I'm tense and nervous
And I can't relax ♪
♪ I can't sleep. 'cause my bed's on fire ♪
♪ Don't touch me. I'm a real live wire ♪
♪ Psycho killer. qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
[automated voice] You exceed
the authorized speed limit.
♪ Run. run. run. run. run. run. run away ♪
[automated voice] Take the next exit.
♪ Oh-ho-ho-ho. aye-yi-yi-yi-yi ♪
♪ Ce que J'ai fait ce soir-là ♪
♪ Ce qu'elle a dit ce soir-là ♪
♪ Réalisant mon espoir ♪
♪ Je me lance vers la gloire. okay ♪
[automated voice]
You're arriving in Chérence.
♪ Yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah
Yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah. yeah ♪
♪ We are vain and we are blind ♪
♪ I hate people when they're not polite ♪
♪ Psycho killer. qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
[song fades]
[Lilian in English] There he is.
[indistinct chatter]
[sighs] Jesus.
[dog barking]
[indistinct chatter continues]
- Shit.
- [indistinct voice]
[engine starts]
Oh. my God.
[alert sounding]
[seagulls squawking]
[Gaby on voicemail]
Lilian. you've disappeared.
I'm worried. you know.
Did they change the lock?
Remember dinner at Julien's tonight.
Don't forget. He'll be so happy.
[indistinct chatter]
[on voicemail]
Hello. Dr. Steiner. it's Pierre Hallan.
I didn't want to surprise you...
My wife and I are suing to be reimbursed
for the 40.000 euros I spent seeing you.
My lawyer sent a letter.
Don't take it badly.
[wife interrupts]
He saw a hypnotist once and quit!
You crook! You'll pay us back--!
[in French] Pain in the ass!
- [thumping on car]
- [man shouting indistinctly]
Okay. okay.
[sighs]
[in English] What the fuck? Dicks.
[violin playing "Happy Birthday"]
[man] Merci.
- [laughter]
- [indistinct chatter]
[slurps]
[in French] He killed the aunt.
then his wife.
You never liked oysters.
It's true. I hate them.
I found compromising evidence
he was disposing of.
You searched his trash?
Yeah. it's my job.
Oh. you're trembling.
I'm sure he saw me.
No.
[oven alarm beeping]
[alarm stops]
We're all done.
I'll get the sauce.
[Julien] You refused to have dinner
on my 20th birthday.
Your separation destroyed my childhood.
And now... [laughs]
It's really not cool.
Julien. listen.
We owe you nothing.
Our intimacy is our own.
our sexuality is our own.
Ask yourself.
"What does it deprive you of?" Hm?
- Herbal tea?
- Please.
[Lilian] We pillage what we desire
and destroy what we never had.
It's classic.
Stop the shrink talk.
As a kid.
I loved hanging around her office.
I'd press my ear against the door.
wondering what they could be saying.
I was fascinated.
But once you've been backstage.
it's hard to believe the magic.
Meaning?
It's all bullshit.
I don't believe you.
[scoffs]
It's not a matter of believing.
You'll find tons of reasons.
It'll always be my fault.
All my fault! Blame the mom.
Vanessa. wait and see.
You've had enough.
Know why you're aggressing me?
In my former life.
you were a militiaman.
You wanted to arrest us.
Excuse me? [scoffs]
You wanted to learn German
back in middle school.
Ha!
To be in the same class as Adrien.
[laughs softly] You loved German.
A's and B's on all your homework.
- Right. Gaby? Yes.
- Yes.
Weird wanting to learn German
with an American mother.
Not speaking your maternal language
is bizarre.
Being good at German makes me a Nazi?
Not a Nazi.
A member of the militia
in Paris. [laughs]
That explains it all.
Okay. [laughs]
Whatever.
Were you a Jewish girl?
I was a young Jewish cellist.
Why?
[Julien] You get the nice role.
[scoffs] What? Everyone here is Jewish!
- Except Vanessa.
- [Julien] Jewish when you decide.
I'm not even circumcised.
- [Vanessa] Julien!
- You hear this?
This is total bullshit.
She'd tell my friends
about my protracted anal stage.
- Not again!
- What are you doing?
Uh. will you listen to me or not?
- Will you listen?
- It's hard not to. You're screaming!
Joseph is asleep!
So quiet!
[sighs] Listen.
You were in the militia in 1942. in Paris.
I was with Paula performing at the Opéra.
There was a conductor.
He was evil. and he was armed.
You're freaking me out.
[Gaby] And what was I?
Nothing. You weren't there.
They wanted to deport us.
among the musicians.
And...
she was pregnant with my child.
I had to flee.
It's you...
who arrested them.
[laid-back music playing over speakers]
You're taking this too far.
Not at all! You don't understand!
It explains everything!
Why we don't get along. why...
you've always been scared of me.
And why I feel ill at ease with you.
But now that we know it.
everything will be better...
We've named things.
we put them into words.
I'll be able to love you
like I couldn't before.
Right. honey?
[Vanessa] You're being mean. Lilian.
We should all go to bed.
I'll check on Joseph.
This is wild.
How could you. Lilian Steiner.
buy into that nonsense of former lives?
Others yes. but not you!
- You're upset to be left out.
- You're so vain!
You're plastered. Let me drive!
I drive better when I'm drunk.
You're going too fast.
- Stop!
- [tires screech]
See. I'm in no state to drive.
[sighs] Listen.
Gabriel. I know it seems crazy.
but I think
I've released Paula's dybbuk.
[exhales]
[window closing]
You don't have to believe in hypnosis.
But I know what I saw in Chérence.
His double life.
the house. the inheritance. the woman.
Maybe she's a cousin.
a neighbor. a friend. who knows?
He killed the aunt. then his wife.
He scratched my car.
stole the last session. the cassette.
Leave it to the police.
They won't do a thing.
They never do.
From the beginning.
he's wanted to scare me.
- I'm a bothersome witness.
- Mm.
And our son was in the Waffen.
[scoffs]
I need you to believe me.
I need you on my side.
Look at me.
When's the last time
I asked you for something?
[beeping]
- What are you doing?
- [GPS] Next destination: Chérence.
I need to know if you've gone mad.
if I should worry.
And believe it or not. now I want to know.
[laughs softly]
Mm-hm.
[thunder rumbling]
Follow me.
[thunder continues]
[Gaby] Come!
[dog barking]
Shut up!
[barking continues]
Shit!
- Come.
- What is it?
- [suspenseful music playing]
- [barking continues]
[raindrops pattering]
It's not his cousin.
[thunder continues]
[woman moaning]
[both moaning]
How old is he?
[suspenseful music continues]
Okay. I'll go.
- What are we doing?
- Our plan.
I'll distract him.
and you look for the cassette.
No. you're right. I'm crazy!
Let's go back.
Gaby!
[doorbell rings]
[door opens]
Uh. I'm sorry to bother you.
Sorry. I...
I ran out of gas.
- Ah. damn!
- [Gaby] Uh...
I'm really sorry.
- My car is down the...
- Yes.
Down there?
Yes. and I saw a light on.
I was wondering if you might have
a jerrican of gas?
- [thunder rumbling]
- A jerrican... Yes. I think I do.
Uh... I'll get dressed. Dry off.
- Come inside.
- I...
I'm under the...
Let's go!
- Wait!
- [Simon] An umbrella.
[thunder continues]
Follow me. It's this way.
[Gaby] Thanks.
Go on!
[Simon] It's in the garage.
No electricity with the humidity...
They're my father-in-law's.
They're not loaded.
- Ah.
- Do you hunt?
Uh. not really.
Me neither. I don't get it.
Waiting all day for an animal.
I usually leave some for the lawn mower.
The jerrican.
Crazy how much junk we keep.
[clinking]
[drawer unlocks]
[boy] Who are you?
[gasps softly]
[breathing nervously]
I'm in your dream.
I'm a nice lady who visits children
to soothe them during storms.
You didn't know?
No.
You'll close your eyes.
and I'll go back into your dream.
Only once you're in bed.
Go on.
[chimes tinkling]
Look at me...
without seeing.
Now...
go back to your bed.
Quietly.
Go on.
[chimes continue tinkling]
[thunder rumbling]
[gasps]
[suspenseful music playing]
[shivers]
- Cold. right?
- [chuckles]
[horn honking]
Well...
[stuttering] I'll leave you.
I'll stop bothering you.
Thanks and goodbye.
- [dog barking
- [thunder rumbling]
He has weapons!
[Lilian] He's dangerous.
Don't go near him. okay?
- [Lilian] It was your idea!
- He has a double life. okay.
Killer or not. it's over.
[Lilian] He killed her.
You have no proof. He can press charges
for breaking and entering.
What do you want?
To have your medical license revoked?
You're right. goddamn it...
[sighs]
It's gone too far.
- Shall we go?
- [Gaby] No. wait.
Ah. non.
Wait for the rain to stop.
[Lilian exhales]
[sniffs] Got a cigarette?
I quit.
[scoffs] Glove compartment...
- [sighs]
- [thunder rumbles]
Why did you leave me?
What?
Pass me the cigarette.
The truth.
I didn't leave anyone. Lilian.
I just gave up.
You stopped loving me. I saw it first.
Then I waited for you.
I knew it wasn't over between us.
You knew?
Yes.
I was waiting for you
to come into my office and say.
"Doctor I have an eye problem.
Can you help me to see more clearly?"
I loved you so much.
Me too.
But I don't want us...
to live together again.
Me neither.
So what do we do?
There must be something...
in the middle.
Being friends?
My friend.
[cell phone ringing]
[automated voice]
Call from "Commissariat."
[continues ringing]
Pierre?
Doctor. please forgive me.
I don't know what got into me...
[officer] Please sit down. ma'am.
But... The anonymous phone calls?
The car? The robbery?
I just wanted to take my cassettes.
I promise I didn't steal anything.
[officer] The swastika too?
What swastika?
[mumbles and stutters]
Very small. near the doorbell.
[sighs]
[officer] Are you going to press charges?
[gentle upbeat music playing]
[indistinct voice on recording]
[Lilian on recording]
Because you want to lie down?
[Paula] Not especially.
It's up to you. You're the boss.
I'm tired. I'm afraid I'll fall asleep.
Do patients ever fall asleep?
They drone on about nothing--
Mothers. parents--
Then start snoring?
Finishing their nights here?
That's an expensive nap.
I'm afraid to fall asleep. yes.
[Lilian] Are you afraid to bore me?
[Paula] No.
Not at all.
I may seem lacking in modesty.
but I don't think so.
On the contrary. [chuckles]
I get the feeling that
when our sessions start.
you're impatient to hear the rest.
Well...
everyone says that.
No?
I mean. everyone secretly hopes it.
Yes. I'm scared to fall asleep.
He won't let me sleep.
[Lilian] Who?
Simon.
- [Lilian] Why are you here?
- [Paula] My husband.
Why am I here?
[player clicks]
Like you. I follow you. surveil you.
And your lock is broken.
the door was open.
You're right.
I should never have come last night.
[mumbles] I want a cigarette. Got a light?
A vice I can't get rid of.
Okay. all right.
I understand. You don't like me.
It's because...
Because you know my wife better than me?
She entrusted me with a piece
of her life--
Tut-tut-tut. I'm not your patient!
Don't do that to me.
[sighs] I am Valérie's father.
Women always choose
their children's fathers.
Paula chose me.
I always respected that.
So why did you kill her? Hm?
You can say anything here. Simon.
You're protected
by doctor-patient confidentiality.
I know you picked up the bottles.
It never crossed your mind
that Paula herself tampered
with the prescription?
That's absurd.
Not for her.
For Pearl.
Pearl?
No.
You want me to believe Paula killed Pearl?
There you go with those words.
Accompany her on her final voyage.
What Pearl asked for.
Paula relieved her of something.
of everything.
I didn't...
I didn't realize it would break her.
No. you're lying.
You killed both of them.
Paula never mentioned Pearl.
Do you think patients tell you everything?
Don't you think
they invent their little lives?
Paula must have loved inventing a life
where I didn't have another woman.
Or you didn't know how to listen.
That's why you record it all.
How did you get that cassette?
You do have a light! Huh.
Yes. the cassette!
Well. maybe...
the night of the robbery.
the door was open.
I came by.
Or else my daughter Valérie came here.
Or why not Paula herself?
[sighs] Do we really care?
Comfy chair.
Life is simple seen from here.
Lie down.
No.
- I said lie down.
- No.
You did a bad job. Lilian. Hm?
You killed her.
I don't mean criminal guilt.
but responsibility.
I'm not guilty.
- I'm not.
- Who said you were?
I said responsible.
not guilty.
See. you don't listen.
Why would I have done it? I loved her.
Paula knew everything. No secrets.
I had no double life. Lilian.
We have only one life.
[heart beating]
We lost her together.
Both of us.
Forever.
[gasping]
[heartbeat continues]
[door closes]
[bell tolling]
[Lilian on recording]
Nothing to say today?
Paula?
[breathing heavily]
- [Paula] It's Pearl.
- [chimes tinkling]
- I lost my Pearl.
- [Pearl] Paula.
[Lilian] What pearl?
Paula. I'm tired.
- [Simon] Pearl asked her...
- I need you.
I lost my Pearl.
- I lost my Pearl.
- [Lilian] What pearl?
[Simon] Paula relieved Pearl of something.
Of everything.
[Paula] I can't live with this.
[breathing heavily]
I can't live with this.
[Simon] I didn't realize
it would break her.
[Paula] I'm so tired.
I feel so tired.
[sighs]
Paula. forgive me.
[guitar scales playing upstairs]
Mom?
Uh-- Sorry. About yesterday.
You've got the wrong floor. ma'am.
My mother never apologizes.
- Want a coffee?
- Yes.
Vanessa's still asleep.
[baby crying]
Let me go.
[crying]
[in English] Hi. Joseph.
Hi. baby.
What a big boy.
- Look at you. big boy.
- [mobile playing lullaby]
Hi. buddy.
Hi there.
Did you just wake up?
Yeah.
I got you.
Joseph.
- Here you go. Here you go. buddy.
- [lullaby stops]
You ready for a little bit more of that?
- Yeah.
- [coos]
[Julien chuckles]
[in French] When you were little.
I put you into the arms
of everyone who came to visit.
I was afraid
you'd grow too attached to me.
I wanted you to be able to survive me.
[dreamy music playing]
[children playing]
Excuse me.
- Uh. same thing. please.
- [waiter] Right away.
And...
What?
Did you ever think...
That what?
What?
That I orchestrated it all.
- You?
- The cassette. the robbery.
[cork pops]
Look.
How long since you last needed me?
No.
You're not that smart.
[chuckles]
Handsome. but...
Thanks a lot. Excuse me.
Actually. it's not...
No!
- It's not good. it's bitter.
- No.
- It's corked.
- He's kidding.
- [waiter] I'm sorry. sir.
- It's fine!
It's just to annoy us.
- He always does this.
- Serve her.
- You scared him.
- I sure did.
- Drink up. You'll see.
- Thank you.
Cheers.
Why do you do that?
To make you laugh.
[sentimental music playing]
[fire crackling]
[doorbell rings]
I never saw that chimney.
You've rearranged the furniture.
Yes.
Does it unsettle you?
A little.
No lights?
It's dark.
That scares you. doesn't it?
Yes.
I can sense it.
It terrifies you
to advance in the dark.
It scares all of us.
[Pierre] You're not recording?
No.
I stopped.
I hear you.
I'm here.
["Don't Go To Strangers"
by J.J. Cale playing]
A PRIVATE LIFE
♪ If I'm standing in a crowd ♪
♪ Call my name. call it loud ♪
♪ Don't go to strangers
Woman. call on me ♪
♪ Wave your arms in the air ♪
♪ Let me know that you're there ♪
♪ When in doubt. oh woman. call on me ♪
♪ Don't leave me here to rust ♪
♪ Don't let me turn to dust ♪
♪ Oh. woman. when in doubt. call on me ♪
♪ If I'm standing in a crowd ♪
♪ Call my name. call it loud ♪
♪ Don't go to strangers
Woman. call on me ♪
[song fades]
[dreamy music playing]
[music fades]
[percussive music playing]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org